Alexandra Eesley

Chicago, IL | (763) 226-9665 | alexandra.eesley@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/aeesley | Portfolio: https://aeesley.github.io/alexandra-eesley-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer and digital marketing expert with extensive entrepreneurship and leadership experience. Known for tackling problem solving with a fresh approach, using a unique ability to switch between data-driven strategy, and beautifully intentional design. Invigorated by fast-paced environments, challenges, collaboration and continuous transformation through learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Node Js, MySQL, Express, Handlebars.js, ReactJS, Github, VS Code, MySgl, Heroku, Bootstrap, Foundations

PROJECTS

VEGURU

GitHub: https://github.com/aeesley/project-2-veguru **Deployed:** https://dry-oasis-44384.herokuapp.com/

Veguru is a user-friendly application that helps users live a healthier lifestyle by providing them with key information about a variety of vegetables. The application utilizes HTML, CSS, JQuery, MySQL, Foundations, Handlebars, Express and utilizes data from INSERT NAME database source. This project was created by a team of four contributors, and presented to a group of 30 developers in a Demo Day simulation.

RESTAURANT ROULETTE

GitHub: https://github.com/k1te-m/Project-1-Restaurant-Roulette **Deployed:** https://k1te-m.github.io/Project-1-Restaurant-Roulette/

Restaurant Roulette is a dynamic application that helps users decide where to eat based on their search location and the current weather conditions for that location. The application utilizes HTML, CSS, JQuery, & Foundations, and pulls in API data from the Open Weather API and Zomato API's. This project was created by a team of two contributors, and presented to a group of 30 developers in a Demo Day simulation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

EESLEY CONSULTING

February 2016 - Present

Owner & Strategic Marketing Consultant

- Built a solopreneur consultancy from scratch to six figures in 3 years, with an average 43% growth YOY.
- Empowered 20+ businesses to complete strategic marketing initiatives to boost growth and catalyze impact.
- Built highly specialized knowledge of Google products to deliver outstanding SEO results and growth for clients.
- Continuously pushed individual growth through learning initiatives, conferences, courses, and networking.
- Managed all aspects of running a small business, from analytics to client communication, to finished deliverables.

URBAN LEASH

October 2015 – February 2016

Director of Marketing & Sales

- Increased lead generation and conversion rates by optimizing partnership, digital and grassroots channels.
- Managed all content generation including website, social media, email campaigns and partnership collateral.
- Hired and managed a team of Brand Ambassadors to increase lead generation and overall brand exposure.
- Developed structures, best practices and reporting for lead optimization and channel growth analysis.
- Analyzed customer trends to discover opportunities for growth, upselling and improved customer retention.

IDS

October 2014 - October 2015

Director of Marketing

- Executed a complete rebrand, including web design, content creation, collateral and creative vision.
- Managed all content creation: website, case studies, PowerPoint presentations, press releases and blogs.
- Designed comprehensive marketing campaigns, boosting customer engagement and generating sales leads.

- Managed external vendor relationships and utilized funds to plan events boosting client engagement and leads.
- Contributed strategic insights as leadership team member, evaluating performance metrics to drive decisions.

TRULY CHICAGO

January 2014 – October 2015

Creator & Owner

- Researched SEO strategies to boost web statistics and implemented a long-tail approach, increasing web traffic.
- Grew a social media presence online to build website referrals and a loyal, engaged community of followers.
- Managed content marketing Interns, helping advance their writing skills, specifically for SEO optimized content.

WILLIS GROUP

Marketing Manager

August 2013 – October 2014

- Created content for and designed all promotional, educational, recruiting communications and blog.
- Designed various microsites promoting affiliate agent membership programs, directly increasing membership

Marketing Coordinator

December 2011 – August 2013

- Worked with the IT Team to re-design the outward aesthetic and internal functionality of the company website.
- Researched and implemented the Salesforce CRM for a new client development department.

EDUCATION

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY Full Stack Development Certificate

Winter 2020

DEPAUL UNIVERSITY
Masters in Business Administration

March 2016

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN - MADISON

Spring 2011

Bachelor of Arts in Strategic Communications with a double major in Spanish.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

SEO, SEM, Social Media Marketing, Email Marketing, Content Creation, Blogging, Video Marketing, Podcast Marketing, Marketing Strategy, Keyword Research, Website Design, Graphic Design, Analytics

PERSONAL & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Project Frontline Covid-19 Support Campaign (Organizer & Founder)

Spring 2020

Break the Silence Community Event (Organizer & Founder)
 True Mentors Leadership Forum

Fall 2018 Summer 2018

LGMC McHenry County

Class of 2018